<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://qdo1010.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://qdo1010.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-03-31T02:15:43+00:00</updated><id>https://qdo1010.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A webpage. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">CAPTCHA, reCAPTCHA, duolingo</title><link href="https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/captcha/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CAPTCHA, reCAPTCHA, duolingo"/><published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/captcha</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/captcha/"><![CDATA[<p>a fun interview with Luis von Ahn in a podcast called How I Built This, about how words meant to gatekeep become words that open the door for many.</p> <p>https://www.npr.org/2020/05/22/860884062/recaptcha-and-duolingo-luis-von-ahn</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="generic-posts"/><category term="void,"/><category term="existing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[pt2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">writing to the void</title><link href="https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/void/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="writing to the void"/><published>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/void</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/void/"><![CDATA[<p>As these words are being written, or typed up, microscopic light emitting diodes radiate photons accordingly, some hitting neurons and causing long term structural changes, so much so that these cells can replay the same sequence of words for days to follow. As soon as an appropriate combination of keys is pressed, electrons also get trapped in nanoscopic structures and all the contents written to this point are also saved for years to come.</p> <p>But words written here are tied to the existence of the laptop and the person writing these words. Unless the person writing these words decided to embed these words in electromagnetic wave and delivered them to a remote data center, in which case the existence of these words would then be tied to the existence of electrons in nanoscopic structures elsewhere. And if an individual elsewhere requested electromagnetic waves containing these words to be delivered to them via the data center, microscopic light emitting diodes would radiate photons accordingly, some hitting neurons causing long term structural changes, in which case these words now live in the memory of the aforementioned individual.</p> <p>There is also a scenario where words were typed up but then deleted or forgotten, in which case they now live in the void. Photons hitting neurons making no impact and electron charge gets dropped to none. Are words not yet written, or are they simply being written to the void?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="generic-posts"/><category term="void,"/><category term="existing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[pt2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">words yet to be written</title><link href="https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="words yet to be written"/><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qdo1010.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/"><![CDATA[<p>Struggling to write even the first few words for this because this site should not have been made in the first place, for so many reasons not yet written, but now that it’s somewhat taking shape, it would be a waste to leave it unfinished. Still hesitating to put in more words though. So many words were written and deleted. So much time has passed. It amazes me that these are the words left untouched.</p> <blockquote><p>I always find comfort in words placed here. If writing is anything like musical composition, then these words are both tension and release.</p><cite><a class="citation" href="#"></a></cite></blockquote> <p>And if struggling is the first word that starts this post, what is the best word to indicate the end.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="generic-posts"/><category term="words,"/><category term="written"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[first of many to come]]></summary></entry></feed>